<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<collection>
 <document>
  <id>
   7742387
  </id>
  <passage>
   <infon key="type">
    title
   </infon>
   <offset>
    0
   </offset>
   <text>
    Effect of retinoic acid on Nm/23 nucleoside diphosphate kinase and components of cyclic adenosine monophosphate-dependent signalling in human neuroblastoma cell lines.
   </text>
  </passage>
  <passage>
   <infon key="type">
    abstract
   </infon>
   <offset>
    168
   </offset>
   <text>
    The effects of retinoic acid on components of the cAMP-dependent signalling system were examined in two related human neuroblastoma cell lines SK-N-SH-F (SHF) and SK-N-SH-N (SHN). Retinoid treatment for a week significantly increased the concentration of intracellular cAMP and the levels of activity of protein kinase A and adenylate cyclase in both cell lines. Retinoic acid treatment also caused a very marked translocation of nucleoside diphosphate kinase from the cytosol to the membrane fraction. The increases in cyclic nucleotide and protein kinase A activity were observed to occur as early as within 1 and 2 days respectively and preceded or were concurrent with the onset of observable morphological differentiation. Results also indicated that agents which elevated intracellular cAMP caused neuronal differentiation and blunted retinoic acid-induced melanocytic differentiation in SHF cells. However, increases in cAMP brought about by treatment of SHF cells with retinoic acid alone were several-fold smaller and thus insufficient to induce neuritogenesis in these cells. The results as a whole indicate that one overall effect of retinoic acid treatment is to upgrade the activity of components of the cAMP-dependent signalling system in both neuroblastoma cell lines. However, retinoic acid causes the SH-F and SH-N cell lines to differentiate along different routes which means that the upgrading responses may be related to more general aspects of differentiation rather than to specific phenotype expression.
   </text>
  </passage>
 </document>
 </collection>